He clobbers the mob
Black Belt Jones is a action, comedy, crime film directed by Robert Clouse.
Jones is a secret agent who has gone into semi-retirement, concentrating
instead on teaching the martial arts to inner city youths.
The karate school is run by a kindly old coot named Pops.
His gambling debts, however, bring the local thug, Pinky, down on him.
To make matters worse, Pinky is then hired by some white thugs who want to get a hold of
the property Pops' school occupies so they can build a shopping mall.
When things get heavy, Black Belt Jones leaps into action.
Only he's not alone.
Pops' daughter, Sidney, shows up to lend a hand, proving herself every
bit as agile and powerful a martial artist as Jones.
Black Belt Jones, played by Jim Kelly.
Sydney, played by Gloria Hendry.
Pop Byrd, played by Scatman Crothers.
Quincy, played by Eric Laneuville.
Toppy, played by Alan Weeks.
Don Steffano, played by Andre Philippe.
Black Belt Jones is a 1974 American blaxploitation martial arts film directed
by Robert Clouse and starring Jim Kelly and Gloria Hendry.
The film is a spiritual successor to Clouse's prior film Enter
the Dragon, in which Kelly had a supporting role.
Here, Kelly features in his first starring role as the eponymous character, a local hero
who fights the Mafia and a local drug dealer threatening his friend's dojo.
The film explores themes of martial arts, blaxploitation cinema, black belt.
The tone is lighthearted.